Guide to the Time Inc. Publicity Files 1923-1984 MS 3009-RG 46
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Publicity Files
1923-1984
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 46
12 Linear feet in 11 boxes
A collection of press clippings documenting outside perception of Time Inc. regarding the company's publications, activities, and personnel spanning 1923 to 1984.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Historical Note
According to Time Inc. archivist Bill Hooper, Public Relations compiled the clippings and gradually turned them over to the Archives. The collection itself does not disclose who created or maintained it. Since a 1996 inventory of the Time Inc. archives located in Corporate Editor James Gaines's files identifies the Publicity Files as a discrete collection, it has not been included with the Corporate Public Affairs records. Most of the collection appears to have once been pages in scrapbooks, but were removed from the scrapbooks and foldered prior to acquisition.
Citation:
Hooper, Bill. Email to Holly Deakyne, 5 October 2016.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library. Additional news clippings about Time Inc. are in Time Inc. News Clippings (MS 3009-RG 20) and Time Inc. Corporate Public Affairs Department Records (MS 3009-RG 19).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of press clippings from non-Time Inc. newspapers and magazines that pertain to Time Inc. publications, activities or personnel, spanning from 1923 to 1984. The clippings' emphasis ranges from incidental mentions of Time Inc. personnel present at an event or Time magazine's cultural influence to entire articles or editorials on a Time Inc.-related topic. Company cofounder Henry Luce is a common topic for several decades of the collection's span, including stories on his political opinions (e.g. advocacy for United States involvement in the Second World War, anti-communism, and the China Lobby supporting the Republic of China) and aspects of his personal life known to the press such as his religious beliefs and marriage. Time Inc.'s role and influence in journalism, culture, and business are frequent topics. While most folders represent only a date range, some are also organized by particular topic, such as reactions to the death of Henry Luce or reviews of Robert T. Elson's published histories of Time Inc. The clippings are largely from United States sources, although other English-language sources, such as Canadian and British, are present and there is a small amount of foreign-language clippings.
Clippings (information artifacts); Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Corporation records; Journalism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Newspaper clippings.; Organization files; Press clippings.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives.; Time, inc. -- History.
- Publicity: 1923-25, 1923-1925 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 1)
- Publicity: 1926 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 2)
- Publicity: 1927 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 3)
- Publicity: 1928 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 4)
- Publicity: 1929 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 5)
- Publicity: 1930 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 6)
- Publicity: 1931 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 7)
- Publicity: 1932 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 8)
- Publicity: 1933 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 9)
- Publicity: 1934 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 10)
- Publicity: 1935 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 11-12)
- Publicity: 1936 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 13-14)
- Publicity: 1936 (Offsite-box 3831, Folder 13)
- Publicity: 1937 (Offsite-box 3832, Folder 1-3)
- Publicity: 1938 (Offsite-box 3832, Folder 4-6)
- Publicity: 1939 (Offsite-box 3832, Folder 7)
- Publicity: 1940 (Offsite-box 3832, Folder 8-10)
- Publicity: 1941 (Offsite-box 3833, Folder 1-3)
- Publicity: 1942 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3833, Folder 4-5)
- Publicity: 1942 "Smear" Campaign (Offsite-box 3833, Folder 6-7)
- Publicity: 1943 (Offsite-box 3833, Folder 8-9)
- Publicity: 1944 (Offsite-box 3833, Folder 10-11)
- Publicity: 1945 (Offsite-box 3834, Folder 1-2)
- Publicity: 1946 (Offsite-box 3834, Folder 3-4)
- Publicity: 1947 Cleveland Forum (Offsite-box 3834, Folder 5)
- Publicity: 1947 Freedom of the Press Commission (Offsite-box 3834, Folder 6)
- Publicity: 1947 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3834, Folder 7-8)
- Publicity: 1948 (Offsite-box 3834, Folder 9-11)
- Publicity: 1949 (Offsite-box 3835, Folder 1-2)
- Publicity: 1950 (Offsite-box 3835, Folder 3-4)
- Publicity: 1951 (Offsite-box 3835, Folder 5-6)
- Publicity: 1952 (Offsite-box 3835, Folder 7-9)
- Publicity: 1953 (Offsite-box 3835, Folder 10-12)
- Publicity: 1954 (Offsite-box 3836, Folder 1-2)
- Publicity: 1954 Stories on Shepley/Blair The Hydrogen Bomb Book (Offsite-box 3836, Folder 3)
- Publicity: 1955 (Offsite-box 3836, Folder 4)
- Publicity: 1956 (Offsite-box 3836, Folder 5)
- Publicity: 1957 (Offsite-box 3836, Folder 6-8)
- Publicity: 1958 (Offsite-box 3836, Folder 9-11)
- Publicity: 1959 (Offsite-box 3837, Folder 1-3)
- Publicity: 1960 (Offsite-box 3837, Folder 4-5)
- Publicity: 1961 (Offsite-box 3837, Folder 6-8)
- Publicity: 1962 (Offsite-box 3837, Folder 9-10)
- Publicity: 1963 (Offsite-box 3837, Folder 11-13)
- Publicity: 1964 January-June (Offsite-box 3838, Folder 1-3)
- Publicity: 1964 July-December (Offsite-box 3838, Folder 4-6)
- Publicity: 1965 (Offsite-box 3838, Folder 7-9)
- Publicity: 1966 (Offsite-box 3838, Folder 10-12)
- Publicity: 1967 Death of Henry Robinson Luce (H.R.L.) Foreign (Offsite-box 3839, Folder 1-2)
- Publicity: 1967 Death of Henry Robinson Luce (H.R.L.) U.S. (Offsite-box 3839, Folder 3-6)
- Publicity: 1967 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3839, Folder 7-8)
- Publicity: 1968 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3839, Folder 9-10)
- Publicity: 1968 Reviews of Elson, Kobler Books (Offsite-box 3839, Folder 11-12)
- Publicity: 1969 (Offsite-box 3840, Folder 1-2)
- Publicity: 1970 (Offsite-box 3840, Folder 3)
- Publicity: 1971 (Offsite-box 3840, Folder 4-5)
- Publicity: 1972 (Offsite-box 3840, Folder 6)
- Publicity: 1972 Life's Demise (Offsite-box 3840, Folder 7-13)
- Publicity: Life's Demise 1972-73, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 1)
- Publicity: 1972 Reviews of Swanberg's Book Luce and His Empire (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 2-3)
- Publicity: 1973 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 4)
- Publicity: 1974 Reviews of Elson's History, Volume II, 1973 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 5)
- Publicity: 1974 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 6)
- Publicity: 1974 Cable-Regulatory (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 7)
- Publicity: 1975 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 8)
- Publicity: 1976 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 9)
- Publicity: 1977 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 10)
- Publicity: 1978 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 11)
- Publicity: 1979 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 12)
- Publicity: 1979/80 Discover, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 13)
- Publicity: 1980 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 14)
- Publicity: 1980 Top Management Turnover (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 15)
- Publicity: 1981 Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 16)
- Publicity: 1981 Washington Star (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 17)
- Publicity: 1983-84 Miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 18)
- Publicity: Time Inc. 1968-75, 1968-1975 (Offsite-box 3841, Folder 19)